Guide to the Jerald Brauer Papers 1925-1999
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Research and Course Notes, 1938-1975
  - Subseries 2: Research Documents and Notes
    - British Literature Notes, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Historical Research, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - American History Notes, n. d. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Church History Notes, 1943 (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Theology and Ethics Notes, 1954 (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Ethics and Psychology Notes, 1940-1941 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Theology and Liberalism Notes, 1948 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Twentieth-Century Philosophy, 1940-1941 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Philosophy, Plato, n. d. (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - English 101, Notes and Essays, 1939 (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - American Literature, Essays and Notes, 1937 (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Philosophy Outlines, n. d. (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Philosophy, Nineteenth Century, 1942 (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - History of Christianity, Southern, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - History of Christianity, Southern, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Church History Notes, Jonathan Edwards, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Church History American Colonial Thought, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Religion in America, 1750-1840, 1947-1949 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Religion in America, 1750-1840, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Church History, New England Puritanism, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Church History, New England Puritanism, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Colonial America, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - American Church History, 1760-1810, 1949 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Christianity in America, 1860-1918, 1952 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Reformation Notes, 1991 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Religion and Regionalism Notes, 1981 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Barnes, Anti-Slavery Impulse, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Religion in America, Book of Mormon Notes, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Deism in American Church History, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Deism and the Church, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Church History, Sources and Methods, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Religion in America, 1977 (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Roger Williams, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Church History, American Colonial, n. d. (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - Church History, Bibliography, 1955 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Cherry, New England Puritanism, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - American Church History, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Black Experience Seminar, 1969 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Church History bibliography, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Religion and Equality, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - American Experience, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - American Religion, Course Materials, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Church History, Religion in America, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - American Church History Survey, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Theocracy Notes, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - America to 1865, n. d. (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Theocratic Ideal, 1954 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Schweitzer, 1944 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Harnack Paper, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Carthage College History, Notes, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Zoology, Notes and Sketches, 1940 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Carthage College, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - "The Concept of History," Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Brauer Lecture Notes, 1950s (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Arbaugh, "Ethics Applied," 1941 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Church History 343, Notes (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Book Reviews (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Lectures, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Reformation Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Millennialism Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Radical Puritanism Notes, 1974 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Puritan Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Puritan Mysticism, 1981 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Historical Theology, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Traynor/Fox Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Fox Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - William Dell Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - William Dell Notes, 1962 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Radical Puritanism, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Mysticism Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Puritanism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Sterry Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Mysticism Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Trocltsch, Puritanism Notes, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Puritanism, Cope, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Puritanism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Puritanism, Bibliography, n. d. (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - Mysticism Notes, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Vane Notes, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Puritan Radicalism and Mysticism, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Feinberg, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Historical Theology, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Puritan Mysticism, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Puritan Revolution, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Mystical Marriage, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Rous Notes, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Rous and Fox Notes, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Puritan Revolution Bibliography, 1957-1959 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Theology Historical, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - English Poets, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Church History Bibliography, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Puritan Radicalism, n. d. (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Puritan Radicalism Bibliography, 1976 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Puritanism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - English Puritanism, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Puritanism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Radical Puritanism, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews, Slavery, 1974 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Syllabi, Brauer Classes, 1975-1990 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Church History Study Questions, 1950-1956 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Modernity as Temptation, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Church History Exam Questions, 1954-1984 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - History of Christianity Exam Questions, 1978-1984 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Church History Questions, 1946-1947 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - May Article with Notes, 1964 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Mead Article with Notes, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - Church History Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - Church History Bibliographies, 1967-1969 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Religion in American History Bibliographies, 1970 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Nineteenth-Century Pulpit in America Notes, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Demos Workshop Materials, 1974 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews, 1949-1950 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Bibliographies, 1983 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - American Mesmerism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Revivalism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - United States Revivalism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Revivalism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Mead Bibliographies, 1966-1977 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Pentecostal Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Revivalism Bibliography and Notes, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Magic Bibliography, 1974 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Revivalism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - 1876 Centennial Notes, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - New England Puritanism Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Canadian Church History Bibliography, n. d. (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Religion in America Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - American Church History Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - American Urbanism Bibliographies, 1979 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Millennialism Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - American Church History Bibliography, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - American Church History, Bibliography, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Religion in Colonial America Bibliography, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Hartford Bibliography, 1951 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Religion in Colonial America Bibliography, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Church History in America Notes, n. d. (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Church History, Medieval Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Church History, Eastern Orthodox, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Eastern Theology Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Systematic Theology Outlines, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Western Religions Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Modern Judaism Notes, 1979-1981 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Bibliographies, 1979-1982 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Religion and Society Notes (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Church History Bibliographies, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Church History, Mead Lecture, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Roman Catholicism Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Roman Catholicism Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Judaism Materials, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Religion in Western Culture Notes, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Church History, Anabaptism, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - English Reformation Bibliography, 1982 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Methodology, 1977 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Shirley Jackson Case Notes, 1971 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Medieval Theology, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Church History, Medieval, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Zen Documents and Notes, 1955-1983 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Revivalism and Music, Bibliography and Notes, n. d. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Revivalism and Music Notes and Documents, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Revivalism and Music Notes and Documents, n. d. (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Revelation and Theology Galley, n. d. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Revelation and Theology Galley, n. d. (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - File cards, research notes, n. d. (Box 85)
    - File cards, research notes, n. d. (Box 86)
- Series VI: Sermons and Speeches, 1946-1999
  Series VI: Sermons and Speeches contains draft copies of sermons and speeches given by Brauer. They include commencement addresses, memorials, and academic lectures.
  - Riedel Sermon, 1947 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - "The Mystical Element" 1949 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - "Lutheran Theological Education Today" 1950 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, 1950s (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Thoughts on Sermons, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Lectures, 1951 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Hamline Lecture, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Reformation Speech, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Brauer Television Appearance, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Speeches, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Social Welfare, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - University of Michigan, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - Speeches, 1956 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - Education in the USA, 1957 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - "Rule of Saints," Techrey Lecture, 1958 (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - Speeches and Sermons, 1957-1958 (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - Sermon Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 87, Folder 17)
  - Knox College, 1957 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - Concordia Paper, 1958 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - "Education in the Space Age," 1959 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - FTF Speeches, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - Seattle Council of Churches, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - Florida Lectures, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - "Marxism," Ohio State, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Political Thought Notes, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Detroit, 1959 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Religion Faces the Atomic Age, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Franklin and Marshall College, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Ohio Speeches, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - Wabash Center, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - University of New Mexico, 1960 (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - Speeches, 1960-1965 (Box 88, Folder 15)
  - Valparaiso Conference, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 16)
  - National Council of Churches, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 17)
  - National Council of Churches of Christ, 1962 (Box 88, Folder 18)
  - Lecture on Laity, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 19)
  - Gettysburg Lectures, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 20)
  - Hartwick College, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - Laity Lectures, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 22)
  - "The Theological Issues," 1963 (Box 88, Folder 23)
  - "Continuing Problems," 1963 (Box 88, Folder 24)
  - "Generalities," 1963 (Box 88, Folder 25)
  - Radiation and Social Ethics, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Radiation and Social Ethics, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Radiation and Social Ethics, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Radiation and Social Ethics, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Address to Lutheran Colleges, 1963 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Speeches, 1963-1964 (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Wagner College, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Theological Education Speeches, 1967-1968 (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - LSTC Lecture, 1967 (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Speeches and Notes, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Dialogue with Altizer, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - "Student Revolution," 1968 (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - Roanoke College, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Synodical Presidents Conference, 1968 (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - "Adam in a New Age," 1968 (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary, 1969-1979 (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Beth Emet, Sermon, 1969 (Box 89, Folder 17)
  - Wasau Speech, 1969 (Box 89, Folder 18)
  - Genetics and Ethics, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Convocation Address, 1970 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - "The Passing of Freedom," 1970 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Findley College, 1972 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Carthage College Address, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Jewish Center, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - "Changing Role of Religion in Contemporary Culture," 1974 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - "Recollection and Vision," 1975 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Armstrong Lectures, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Kalamazoo College, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Kalamazoo College, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Roanoke College, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - AAR, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - AAR, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Wagner Conference, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - World Hunger Speech, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - Augustana Lutheran Sermon, 1976 (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Gettysburg Seminary Speech, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Perrin Memorial, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 19)
  - LACUSA Speech, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Hutchins Memorial, 1977 (Box 90, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 22)
  - Organization of American Historians, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 23)
  - Christian Theological Seminary, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 24)
  - LSTS Lecture, 1979 (Box 90, Folder 25)
  - "State of the Divinity School," 1979 (Box 90, Folder 26)
  - Lutheran Speech, 1980 (Box 90, Folder 27)
  - "Anti-Semitism," 1980 (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - Carthage Speech, 1980 (Box 90, Folder 29)
  - "Religion and Public Order in American," 1981 (Box 90, Folder 30)
  - Columbus Lawyers Group, 1981 (Box 90, Folder 31)
  - Krauth Lecture, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 32)
  - Tubingen, 1983-1985 (Box 90, Folder 33)
  - Theological Conference, 1982 (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Green Lake Conference, 1983 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Regionalism Conference, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - "Bishops and Lutherans," 1985 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Hoover Lecture, 1984 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Calvinism Then and Now, 1986-1987 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Retreat, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - "Religion and Social Change," 1986 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Eliade Memorial, 1986 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Eliade Conference, 1987 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Sermons, 1991 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Kitagawa Memorial, 1992 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - Wittenberg Address, 1992 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - Brauer Sermons, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Speeches and Addresses, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - Convocation, 1993 (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - Shils Tradition, 1994 (Box 91, Folder 17)
  - Lutheran World Federation, n. d. (Box 91, Folder 18)
  - Jewish Theological Seminary, n. d. (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - Fortress Lecture, n. d. (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - "Apostolic Woman," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Theological Education Speech, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - "Problem of Life," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - "Terrain of History," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Vikstrom Lecture, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Meditation, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Second Inaugural Address, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Lutheran Sermon, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - University of Tennessee, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Sermon in San Francisco, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Detroit, Krumholtz Lectures, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Rosie Arndt, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - "A View Through a Fence," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - "A Requiem for Ken," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Nuveen Lecture, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - Conference Paper Notes, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 17)
  - AHR Response, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 18)
  - "A Requiem for Ken," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 19)
  - Puritan Piety, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 20)
  - "On Universities," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 21)
  - Vatican Council, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 22)
  - Gerrish Wedding, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 23)
  - Janet Lowell Memorial, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 24)
  - Justice and Reconciliation Notes, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 25)
  - Iowa State Lecture, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 26)
  - Canisius Lecture, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 27)
  - "Catholics and Lutherans," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 28)
  - Speeches on Ministry, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 29)
  - Response to Papers, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Speeches, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 31)
  - Lowell's Comments, n. d. (Box 92, Folder 32)
  - "Requiem for Ken," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 33)
  - "Faculty I have Known," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 34)
  - "Ecumenicism' n. d. (Box 92, Folder 35)
  - "The Modern State and the Church's Responsibility," n. d. (Box 92, Folder 36)
  - Sermons, 1949 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Miami University Speech, 1956 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Religious Motivation, 1957 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Published Lectures, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Commencements, 1957, 1959 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Citizenship, 1958 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Worship Series, 1960 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Suenens, 1964 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Lectures, 1964 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Lutheran Experience, 1976 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Theological Education Speech, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Passing of Freedom, 1970 (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - Justice and Reconciliation, 1970 (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Carthage Speech, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Gettysburg Sermon, 1984 (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Loechler Meditation, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 16)
  - LCA, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 17)
  - Atomic Age Speech, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 18)
  - Tubingen Speech, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 19)
  - Eliade Chair Speech, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 21)
  - Notre Dame Address, n. d. (Box 93, Folder 22)
- Series VII: Paul Tillich (1886-1965), 1954-1994
  Series VII contains personal and professional correspondence between Brauer and Paul and Hannah Tillich as well as secondary materials relating to Tillich including published essays, reviews, and clippings. The Series also includes draft copies of Paul Tillich's diaries later published as My Travel Diary, 1936: Between Two Worlds (1970). Brauer edited the diary for publication and provided an introduction. The diary was one of several memorial projects Brauer worked on after Tillich's death in 1965.
  Paul Tillich was born in Germany in 1886. A philosopher and theologian, Tillich was dismissed from his position as professor of philosophy at University of Frankfurt after Hitler came to power in 1933. Tillich fled to the United States where he became Visiting Professor of Philosophy of Religion at Union Theological Seminary, he went on to serve as Associate Professor of Philosophical Theology (1937-1940, and Professor (1937-1955). When Brauer was an instructor at Union Theological Seminary from 1948 to 1950 he worked as assistant to Tillich. In 1962, Brauer was instrumental in bringing Tillich to the Divinity School as the Nuveen Professor of Theology. Tillich remained at the University for three years, until his death in 1965. The series documents the strong personal and intellectual ties between the two men.
  Additional material correspondence by and about Paul and Hannah Tillich can be found in Series II.
  - Sermons and Articles (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Tillich Notes (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Systematic Theology 1 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Niebuhr Essays (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Syllabi and Book Lists (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - List, Works by Tillich (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Pauck Letters on Tillich (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Tillich at Chicago, 1954-1956 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Tillich at Chicago Continued, 1958-1965 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - William Dean on Tillich (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Williamson Interview about Tillich (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Brauer Lecture on Tillich, 1959 (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - Tillich Newsletter, 1992-1996 (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - Tillich Conference,1975-1976 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Tillich at Chicago Essays, 1978 (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - Eliade Interview (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - Tillich at Chicago with German Translation, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Tillich Reviews, 1960s (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Systematic Theology, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Arthur Jenz on Tillich, 1983 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Reviews, Paul Tillich; His Life and Thought, 1977 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Tillich Diary, Correspondence and Proofs, 1968-1969 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Tillich, 1966 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Tillich Diary, Notes, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Memorials, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Mysticism, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - Between Two Worlds, Draft, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 11)
  - Between Two Worlds, Corrections, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 12)
  - Kucheman on Tillich, 1972 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Tillich Chair, 1971 (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Brauer to H.T., 1973 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - The Future of Religion, 1964-1966 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Proposed Memorial, Udume, 1962-1966 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Diary Publication, Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Diary Publication, Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Tillich Articles1966-1982 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Lippencott, Tillich Publication, 1969-1970 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Proposed Anthology, 1965-1966 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - German Diary, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Tillich Portrait, 1968 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence on Tillich, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Tillich, Intro to Diary (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Paul Oppenheim corrections to Diary (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Tillich, Perspectives, 1967-1969 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Tillich, Diary Footnotes (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Tillich, Memorial (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Hannah Tillich, Correspondence (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - H.T., 1980s (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - H.T., Notes on India (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - H.T., Memoirs (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Tillich, Clippings (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Criterion (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Criterion (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Tillich/Criterion Correspondence (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Future of Religions (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Tillich Family Correspondence (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Tillich Memorial (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Liz (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Tillich, Sympathy and Tribute (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Final Tillich Lecture (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Memorials, Miscellaneous (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Tillich Memorial Park (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Tillich Writings, Miscellaneous (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Tillich Historical Theology (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Tillich/McNeill Course Materials (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Tillich, "My Belief in Faith" (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Theology Notes (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Historical Theology Notes (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - "Systematic Theology," Tillich Outlines (Box 98, Folder 12)
  - Systematic Theology Outlines Continued (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Systematic Theology (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Clipping (german) (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Essays (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - List of Lectures (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Tillich Sermon, "Loneliness and Solitude" (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Time Magazine, 1959, 1965 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Tillich Diary (Box 99, Folder 8)